3220 Madison Ave Apt 4 Boulder, CO 805-405-5670 miranda.butler@colorado.edu mirandabutler.github.io

## **Objective**

To contribute to the growth and understanding within the field of system controls and computer science using past experience and developed problem solving skills.

- Dedicated to working efficiently within teams to meet deadlines while placing safety and quality above all else.
- Consistently work to incorporate innovative ideas to produce more efficient and effective technology.
- Natural ability to effectively interact in a group setting, demonstrated ability to organize, engineer, and generate results.

### **Education**

# **University of Colorado Boulder**

Boulder, CO

B.S. Mechanical Engineering, Computer Science Minor

May 2016

GPA: 3.54 out of 4.0

### **Technical Skills**

Python, C++, MATLAB, LabVIEW, SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, Java, Arduino, Mathematica, LaTeX, HTML, Laser Cutter, Lathe, Mill, Drill Press, MS Office

#### Coursework

System Dynamics, Computer Aided Design, Component Design, Microsystems Integration, Circuits for Mechanical, Computer Systems, Data Structures, Algorithms

# Awards/Memberships

Dean's List (Fall 2011, Spring 2012, Spring 2013), Engineering GoldShirt Program, Engineering Honors Program

## **Engineering Experience**

### National Institute of Standards and Technology

Boulder, CO

Guest Researcher in the Antenna Metrology Project,

Spring 2012-Present

## RF Technology Division

- Designed and assembled quasi-optical scanning system used to visualize mmWave scattering off of objects. Wrote LabVIEW code to drive a motor over a specified x-y grid and measure RF energy at each point on the grid. Analyzed the data acquired and refocused the image to improve the system.
- Constructed an automated system for power level reference.
- Developed an optical beam profiler system using a webcam and Gaussian fit model.
- Designed and manufactured custom parts using AutoCAD Inventor.
- Wrote MATLAB code for a graphical user interface.
- Awarded research fellowship via the Professional Research Experience Program.

## **AMTL: In Vivo Disturbance Simulator**

Boulder, CO

For Control of Lifesaving Mobile Capsule Surgical Robots

Fall 2015-Present

# Systems Engineer

- Designed and casted 2x and 1x scaled colon molds using 3D printing
- Prototyped, designed, manufactured and controlled disturbance table with 4 DOF to mimic patient breathing and shifting using stepper motors for linear actuation and MATLAB control

PennApps: Patches

University of Philadelphia

Hacker January 2016

- Built a universal android app and website for animal shelters
  to list pet adoption info to help increase homeless pet adoptions
- Constructed and populated the database using MongoDB
- Contributed to website development written in html and PHP

## **CU Bridges to Prosperity**

Samaca, Bolivia

Design Leader

Summer 2015

- Used AutoCAD to designed a pedestrian footbridge in Bolivia
- Sourced materials and participated in construction of the bridge

### **Smart Alarm Clock**

University of Colorado Boulder

Student Spring 2015

 Design and assembly of a Smart Alarm Clock that was controlled by pressure sensors and an Arduino

## **Component Design**

University of Colorado Boulder

Manufacturing Engineer

Fall 2014

- Used SolidWorks for design of a drill powered bike
- Personally manufactured custom parts

### Kids Around the World

Vicente Guerrero, Mexico

Volunteer January 2013

- Worked as a team to build three playgrounds in rural areas of Mexico and New Orleans
- Used tools to assemble parts, map out holes and analyze diagrams

YOU'RE@CU

University of Colorado Boulder

Student Spring 2012

Tested detention pond water for hydroxyl radical formation

### Owen's Backpack

University of Colorado Boulder

Student Fall 2011

 Constructed a backpack that holds an oxygen tank without it moving or causing stress on clients back

### **Publications**

Researcher NIST

Electromagnetically Induced Transparency with Rydberg Atoms in October 2015
 Strong Microwave Fields,

(To be submitted October 2015 to Physical Review Applied)

Researcher

 MM-Wave Near-Field Measurements Using Coordinated Robotics, (Submitted to IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation) June 2015

Researcher

 Automated Setup of a 90-140 GHz Power Reference, (PREP Poster Session) Fall 2014

Student University of Colorado Boulder

 Detention for hydroxyl radical formation, (YOU'RE@CU Poster Session) Spring 2012

# **Work Experience**

Teaching Assistant for Computational Methods

University of Colorado Boulder

Helped with assigned projects

Fall 2015

Flatirons Golf Course

Boulder, CO

Manage and organize tee sheet, course ranger, cashier

Present

Andrews Hall Tutoring Coordinator and Tutor

University of Colorado Boulder

 Initiated and organized the tutoring program by recruiting, scheduling, tutoring, analyzing effectiveness and implementing improvements August 2013-May 2014

Teaching Assistant for Pre-Calculus for Engineers

University of Colorado Boulder

 Helped with questions during recitation, held office hours, graded Fall 2012

Lab Assistant in Environmental Engineering Lab

University of Colorado Boulder

 Prepared samples, ran samples through spectrophotometer and solar simulator Fall 2012

### Leadership and Volunteering

Engineering GoldShirt Program Scholar and Mentor

University of Colorado Boulder

Leading study sessions, bonding events, mentoring individuals, and volunteering

August 2011-Present

Engineering Honors Program - Member

University of Colorado Boulder

Participate in Honors program and classes

August 2012-Present

Tutor at Arapahoe High School

University of Colorado Boulder

Tutored geometry and mentored students

Spring 2014

Technology and Engineering to Advance Math and Science

Longmont, CO

 Introduced engineering concepts to 5<sup>th</sup> graders and encouraged them to succeed

Spring 2013

## Interests

Golfweek Amateur Tour Denver, CU Club Swim Team, Young Life College, Christian Crusaders Worship Band, The Annex, Boulder Indoor Soccer, CU Intramural Soccer and Tennis, skiing, guitar, yoga, Ableton, Arduino